<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/scripts/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/"><channel><title>@sween</title><description>A Man with Good Intentions</description><link>https://sween.github.io</link><item><title>Using MDX</title><link>https://sween.github.io/blog/using-mdx</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sween.github.io/blog/using-mdx</guid><description>Learning how to use MDX in Astro</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This theme comes with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.astro.build/en/guides/integrations-guide/mdx/&quot;&gt;@astrojs/mdx&lt;/a&gt; integration installed and configured in your &lt;code&gt;astro.config.ts&lt;/code&gt; config file. If you prefer not to use MDX, you can disable support by removing the integration from your config file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why MDX?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MDX is a special flavor of Markdown that supports embedded JavaScript &amp;#x26; JSX syntax. This unlocks the ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.astro.build/en/guides/markdown-content/#mdx-features&quot;&gt;mix JavaScript and UI Components into your Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; for things like interactive charts or alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have existing content authored in MDX, this integration will hopefully make migrating to Astro a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how you import and use a UI component inside of MDX.&lt;br&gt;
When you open this page in the browser, you should see the clickable button below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;import { Button } from &apos;astro-pure/user&apos;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mdxjs.com/docs/what-is-mdx&quot;&gt;MDX Syntax Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.astro.build/en/guides/markdown-content/#markdown-and-mdx-pages&quot;&gt;Astro Usage Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.astro.build/en/reference/directives-reference/#client-directives&quot;&gt;Client Directives&lt;/a&gt; are still required to create interactive components. Otherwise, all components in your MDX will render as static HTML (no JavaScript) by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded><h:img src="undefined"/><enclosure url="undefined"/></item><item><title>What Is 3D Rendering? Complete Guide to 3D Visualization</title><link>https://sween.github.io/blog/3d-rendering</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sween.github.io/blog/3d-rendering</guid><description>3D imagery has the power to bring cinematic visions to life and help accurately plan tomorrow’s cityscapes. Here, 3D expert Ricardo Ortiz explains how it works.</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;3D rendering is all around us. From huge action movies to car commercials to previews of upcoming buildings or product designs, 3D visualization has become so widespread and realistic that you probably don’t even know it’s there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this introductory piece, Chaos’ Ricardo Ortiz explains the basics of 3D rendering, from the computational methods that create imagery to the artistic techniques that create great computer-generated (CG) content and its various uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is 3D Rendering?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, 3D rendering is the process of using a computer to generate a 2D image from a digital three-dimensional scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate an image, specific methodologies and special software and hardware are used. Therefore, we need to understand that 3D rendering is a process—the one that builds the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sween.github.io/sween/_astro/nikola-arsov-still-life-interior-design-vray-3ds-max-05-930px.DoY3_oVo_2bk04W.webp&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Types of 3D rendering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can create different types of rendered image; they can be realistic or non-realistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A realistic image could be an architectural interior that looks like a photograph, a product-design image such as a piece of furniture, or an automotive rendering of a car. On the other hand, we can create a non-realistic image such as an outline-type diagram or a cartoon-style image with a traditional 2D look. Technically, we can visualize anything we can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How is 3D rendering used?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D rendering is an essential technique for many industries including architecture, product design, advertising, video games and visual effects for film, TV and animation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In design and architecture, renders allow creative people to communicate their ideas in a clear and transparent way. A render gives them the chance to evaluate their proposals, experiment with materials, conduct studies and contextualize their designs in the real world before they are built or manufactured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the media and entertainment industries, 3D rendering is fundamental to the creation of sequences and animations that tell stories, whether we’re watching an animated movie, a period drama, or an action sequence with explosions, ships from the future, exotic locales, or extraterrestrial creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sween.github.io/sween/_astro/thanos-dd-single-image-004a.DUX4VGf-_14oeu4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, the evolution of computer graphics in these industries has replaced traditional techniques. For example, special effects are being replaced by visual effects, which means stunt people no longer risk their lives in car crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In advertising, I would dare to say that 90% of automotive commercials are CG—or even more. In the architecture industry, many traditional techniques to create representations, such as scale models, have been replaced with photorealistic imagery to ensure we can see exactly how something will look once it’s built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerating processes, reducing costs and the demand for better quality results have helped technology evolve. Hardware is more powerful than ever and the switch to CG was inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How is a 3D rendered image generated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two pieces of software, with different characteristics, are used to computer-generate images and animations: render engines and game engines. Render engines use a technique called ray tracing, while game engines use a technique called rasterization—and some engines mix both techniques, but we will talk about that later on.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><h:img src="/sween/_astro/thumbnail.DzZDiYKA.jpg"/><enclosure url="/sween/_astro/thumbnail.DzZDiYKA.jpg"/></item><item><title>The Impact of Technology on the Music World</title><link>https://sween.github.io/blog/music-journey</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://sween.github.io/blog/music-journey</guid><description>The evolution of music is a symphony of creativity, rhythm, and technology.</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of music is a symphony of creativity, rhythm, and technology. From the humble beginnings of acoustic instruments to the present-day digital era, the relationship between music and technology has been transformative. In this article, we will explore the historical milestones, digital revolution, and emerging technologies that have shaped the music world. Join us on a journey through the chords of innovation as we discuss how technology has changed music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Historical Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marriage of music and technology dates back centuries, with pivotal moments shaping the industry. The invention of the phonograph by Thomas Edison in the late 19th century marked the first time music could be recorded and replayed. Subsequent milestones, such as the electric guitar and the synthesizer, revolutionized music creation, paving the way for new genres and sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These technological leaps didn&apos;t merely shape the musical landscape of their time but laid a foundation for the continuous evolution of the intersection between music and technology. As artists embraced these innovations, they unlocked new avenues for creativity, paving the way for diverse sounds and genres that have become integral to the vibrant tapestry of the modern music industry. The historical perspective illuminates the symbiotic relationship between music and technology, highlighting the transformative impact that each innovation has had on the way we create, consume, and experience music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Digital Revolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital revolution has been a seismic shift in the music industry, altering how music is consumed, distributed, and produced. The transition from physical formats like CDs and vinyl to digital formats such as MP3s and streaming services has democratized access to music. The ease of streaming has transformed how listeners discover and enjoy music, challenging traditional revenue models while offering unparalleled convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technology in Music Consumption and Distribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Streaming services have become the heartbeat of music consumption, causing a decline in traditional music stores. The accessibility of music online has reshaped distribution channels, impacting both artists and record labels. While it provides exposure to a global audience, it also poses challenges regarding fair compensation for artists. The dynamics of the industry are evolving, reflecting the intricate dance between technology and music.
Music Production and Creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of digital audio workstations (DAWs), software instruments, and electronic production techniques has democratized music creation. Artists now have powerful tools at their fingertips, enabling them to experiment with sounds, collaborate remotely, and produce music independently. This technological shift has broken down barriers, allowing for a diverse array of voices to be heard in the ever-expanding realm of music.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><h:img src="/sween/_astro/thumbnail.Cx18cRmB.jpg"/><enclosure url="/sween/_astro/thumbnail.Cx18cRmB.jpg"/></item></channel></rss>